Evgenii Kazmiruk

Helsinki, Finland

Matinkallio 7 A 3 Espoo, Finland 02230 Phone:+358-40-356-3-809 +7-913-513-94-85

kazmiruk.evgeniy@gmail.com

I'm a developer with strong skills in software engineering and IT management. I have more than 12 years of experience in IT and almost 8 years of experience in lead job positions: developers' team leader, CTO. I have skills in building and managing developers' teams, designing fault-tolerant architecture, organization of developing, testing and release processes, and intercommunication with technical experts from other organizations (Yandex, the Department of Culture, etc.). There are such projects in my portfolio as: a platform for museums, a service for the generation of audio guides from texts, data mining systems for text analyzing, an automated system for museums' mobile apps generation, a social blogging platform, a children's social network, e-shops, different aggregators, and parsers.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SuperMetrics, Helsinki, Finland

Head of engineering

Jan 2022 - Present

As a head of engineering I oversee our engineering group of 6 teams focusing on building, maintaining and expanding our many successful and hugely popular (and, as result, highly loaded) client-facing products. This currently includes six teams dedicated to different product areas. I help focus, manage and grow the teams as well as products along with our product management team.

<u>Development Environment:</u> Linux, Docker, AWS, GCP, PostgreSQL, ReactJs, VueJs, JavaScript, NodeJs, TypeScript, PHP

Smartly.io, Helsinki, Finland

Sep 2021 - Jan 2022

Engineering manager

As an engineering manager I led a development group with several cross functional teams in it. Focus of our group was on automation of customer operations and building data science optimisations which enables more flexible and effective ways of campaign management for customers.

My main focus was in the area of improving ways of working, defining group structure and hiring plan for the group, defining strategic goals and aligning them with company goals.

Main results in the role are defining new group structure, defining and splitting of scope for each of the teams, establishing ways of working and communicating during the transition period. Also on the basis of this plan the future vision of a separate data science group was defined and plan for evolving company structure during the next year.

<u>Development Environment:</u> Linux(Ubuntu), Kubernates, Docker, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, NestJs, TypeScript, NodeJs, ReactJs, Kotlin, Akka, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Python, Flask, PHP

Smartly.io, Helsinki, Finland

Apr 2020 - Aug 2021

Engineering team lead

As a team lead of one of them engineering teams in Smartly I am responsible for keeping the team on the right track. My responsibilities include hiring and onboarding processes, facilitating plannings and technical discussions in the team (alongside with cross team communication), gathering information from other teams and preparing documentation, adjusting processes, tracking people motivation and performance.

In this role I improved team's ways of work and also solved socialisation problems in remote work environment what made our team one of the most motivated in the company (on base of 360 company

wide survey, previously the team was one of the "unhappiest" team in the company), also I increased amount of developers in two times what allowed us to increase effectiveness of the team.

Also together with my team we boosted up completely new automations and optimisations services for a new platform and current plans include improving and extending this service with new features and for other platforms.

<u>Development Environment</u>: Linux (Ubuntu), Kubernates, Docker, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, NestJS, Jenkins, TypeScript, NodeJs, ReactJS, Python, Flask, PHP

Smartly.io, Helsinki, Finland

Feb 2019 - Apr 2020

Software engineer

Smartly.io is a platform for automation of advertisement, creative production and optimisations. I'm working in a cross platform team as a full stack developer. My main responsibilities are development of new and support of existing services. Currently I'm a main maintainer of a couple of services in the company: service for building reports on base of customers data and cross platform service for actions routing between different platforms. Also I made significant contributions on the frontend and built several libraries to reduce duplication in existing source code. I took ownership of the refactoring process for proxy service between MongoDB and PostgreSQL and replaced old oplog logic with streams which allowed our team to significantly simplify source code, increase stability and maintainability.

Also I take active participation in different cross team communications, planning and meetings. Have good overall knowledge of current infrastructure, existing services and teams. Developed and tested an onsite interview challenge on Python for backend developers.

<u>Development Environment</u>: Linux (Ubuntu), Ruby, Ruby On Rails, PostgreSQL, Citus, Redis, Docker, Jenkins, TypeScript, NodeJs, ReactJS

Big Museum, NPO, Saint Petersburg, Russia

Apr 2017 - Feb 2019

Chief technical officer

Big Museum (https://bm.digital) is a joint project of Yandex and Polytechnic Museum. The main objective of the project is the development and popularization of a museum business, as well as providing a convenient interaction platform between museum workers and visitors. Within a framework of my job position, I tackled the tasks of resource management (recruitment of the development team, budgeting, control, and mentoring for programmers and testers, etc.), choice of technologies, development and approval of the application architecture, interaction with technical experts from Yandex, the Department of Culture and different museums, introduction of methodologies and approaches for an effective development, and monitoring and review of assigned tasks.

In a short time, the code and architecture of the prototype were redesigned and this measures allowed us to significantly increase the effectiveness and quality of the product. Also, a mobile application for the Moscow Biennial for Android and iOS platforms was developed for two months (the development was based on React Native framework), a unique content editor for museum workers was created, and integration was carried out for several museum databases. An internal platform for generating museum mobile applications (also based on React Native) and a content management system for them have been developed.

The platform was successfully launched in March of 2018 and received many positive reviews. Nowadays, the project is being developed actively.

Also, our team has solved such tasks as an automatic analysis and linking of materials, building of a fault-tolerant architecture, an indoor navigation system, a photo navigation system, generation of audio guides based on text articles, search, and an image recognition.

<u>Development Environment</u>: Linux (Ubuntu), Python 3.5, wsgi, uwsgi + nginx, WebDAV, Flask, Celery, PostgreSQL 9.x, Redis, Docker, Openstack, Jenkins, javascript, NodeJs, ReactJS, React Native

Big Museum, NPO, Saint Petersburg, Russia

Development Team Leader (Remote)

Within three months my team and I developed a prototype of a museum platform which was successfully presented to investors and received very positive reviews. After that, we began the process of writing and agreeing on technical specifications. Also, we implemented and improved different developmental processes: writing tests and using a code continuous delivery methodology, using Scrum for tasks and sprints control, writing an API with detailed documentation in a Swagger format, building an agile and scalable microservices architecture.

<u>Development Environment</u>: Linux (Ubuntu), Python 3.5, wsgi, uwsgi + nginx, WebDAV, Flask, Celery, PostgreSQL 9.x, Redis, Docker, Openstack, Jenkins, javascript, NodeJs, ReactJS

TopSoft, LLC, Moscow, Russia

Nov 2013 - Jun 2016

Development Team Leader (Remote)

The company had several different projects that were built at different times with different approaches and technologies. The differences between them and difficulties with support forced the company to start developing a common platform for such projects. I was involved in an architecture design and the development of a social-like platform for the company projects. For the first several months, my task involved choosing technologies and creating a prototype. After that I developed a production-ready platform on a stack of technologies such as Python + Django, PostgreSQL, Redis, Gearman for asynchronous tasks and AngularJs for a frontend. Also, I developed a migration tool for mapping an old data structure into new tables. All the projects of the company have been successfully transferred into the new platform (https://temaretik.com) and currently work effectively without any problems.

<u>Development Environment</u>: Linux (Ubuntu), Python 2.7, wsgi, uwsgi + nginx, WebDAV, Django 1.6, gevent, PostgreSQL 9.x, Redis, Gearman, javascript, socket.io, AngularJs, jquery, LESS

Sithi, LLC, Krasnoyarsk, Russia

Nov 2011 – Jun 2014

Senior Python Developer

The company specialized in social networks for children in different countries (Russia, GB, Spain, Czech Republic, Estonia, Vietnam). My task was building an agile and fault-tolerant architecture. I used Python and Flask for a web application with REST API to communicate with a client on Flash (ActionScript) and with mobile applications. I developed a HTML version of the site (http://murclub.ru) and also performed an optimization of queries to MySQL database, caching and refactoring of a legacy code. I built a socket io server based on Redis, websockets and the Gevent library for mobile applications.

<u>Development Environment</u>: Linux (Ubuntu), Unix (FreeBSD), Python 2.7, uwsgi + nginx, Flask, MySQL 5.x, Memcache, Redis, javascript, gevent, socket.io, jquery, actionscript

Factor, LLC, Krasnoyarsk, Russia 2011

May 2011 - Nov

Deputy chief of software development department (adviser)

Before the moment I was hired, the company launched an online shop mediator of Taobao (https://nazya.com). The system was based on Joomla CMS and faced high loads. I introduced different caching methods to the system as a first measure to withstand the high load. After that I was involved in a development process of a new version of the online shop on Python and Django with an optimization of data structures and flows. Also, I built a third party library for an auto caching of django objects. The result of this work was a system which has been used in the company until now and withstands current loads without any problem and also has quite a big safety margin for future growth.

<u>Development Environment</u>: Linux (Ubuntu, Debian), PHP 5.x, Python 2.7, uwsgi + nginx, php-fpm + nginx, Django 1.4, MongoDB 2.x, Redis, Joomla, MySQL 5.x, javascript, jquery

TelecomConsulting, LLC, Krasnoyarsk, Russia

Software Developer

My task was developing different projects for the company and building infrastructure tools for a main company system. I developed two online-shops and a content service for internet providers. After that I was involved into developing a main company project — an aggregation system for tenders (http://multitender.ru) based on the Yii framework. My task was in developing a system for parsing tenders information from different sites, structuring it and storing it in MySQL in a suitable structure. The parsers were written with Python. Also, I developed a CRM system for internal usage based on php, Zend Framework, and MySQL. For the CRM system, I built parsers to collect information about clients from internal documents.

<u>Development Environment</u>: Linux (Ubuntu), Unix (FreeBSD), PHP 5.x, Python 2.6, php-fpm + nginx, apache2, Memcache, MySQL 5.x, ZendFramework, Yii, javascript, jquery

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Platforms: Linux (Ubuntu, Debian), MacOS, Windows

Languages: Python 2/3, JavaScript, Go, Ruby, TypeScript, PHP

Frameworks: Flask, Django, ReactJS, Ruby On Rails

DBMS: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, MySQL

Technologies/tools: Git, NodeJS, Citus

Other: building effective processes of programs development; organization,

mentoring and managing development teams; building an agile and a fault-tolerant architecture for program systems; technical expertise of

systems with any complexity

EDUCATION

2013 - MS, Computer Science, GPA: 5.0

Siberian State Aerospace University, Krasnoyarsk, Russia

Specialization: Intellectual data analysis

Graduated with honors